Guide to the Papers of Army chaplain Walter Marvine, 1874-1936 M1927
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Army chaplain Walter Marvine papers,
1874-1936
M1927
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
4.5 Linear feet (9 boxes)
An archive of 2,868 letters, comprising 8,972 pages (mostly manuscript), with 10 postcards. Included in the page count are several non-correspondence items such as: "Sentinel Duty at Fort Shaw, MT, 1875" (2 pp); "Convocation Address, Fort Spokane, 1895" (8 pp); "A Story of the East TN Mountains" (6 pp); "Diary, 22 Nov-23 Nov, 1900, Tientsin, China" (4 pp); "Some Incidents of My Experiences During the Campaign in China, 1900-01" (13 pp); "Tome written from Ft. Huachuka from Grace to Walter in China, 2 Aug 1900" (220 pp); 2 poems (3 pp); 24 miscellaneous pages of notes; 28 page diary & notes; 5 pages of cash accounts; 3 sermons (21 pp); miscellaneous papers (23 pp); essay on "Chaucer" (5 pp).
Marvine, Walter, Army Chaplain
Biography
Army Chaplain Walter Marvine, 1857-1945, served in the Philippines during the "Philippine Insurrection" (1899-1900), with the 9th Infantry in China at Tientsin during the "Boxer Rebellion" (1900-1901) and with the Expeditionary Brigade during World War One (1917-1918) while serving with Coast Artillery Corps, all dated 1874-1936.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in November 2013.
Scope and Contents
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Michael Brown Rare Books; United States. Army. Chaplain Corp. Unit Ministry Team.; United States. Army. Coast Artillery Corps.; China--History--Boxer Rebellion, 1899-1901--Personal narratives, American.; Philippines--History--Philippine American War, 1899-1902--Personal narratives, American.; World War, 1914-1918--Chaplains--United States--Correspondence.
- Archive information/abstract (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1870-1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1880-1886 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1887-1889 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1890-1891 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1894-1898 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence "Tome", 1900 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1902-1903 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1922-1930 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, undated, {1908-1910} ? (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, undated, {1910-1913} ? (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, undated, {1913-1914} ? (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, undated, {1914-1918} ? (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, undated, {1914-1918} ? (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, undated, {1918-1921} ? (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)